<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>mapping-companies on Rui Yang | Ray Yang, Strategy, U. California, Riverside</title>
    <link>/series/mapping-companies/</link>
    <description>Recent content in mapping-companies on Rui Yang | Ray Yang, Strategy, U. California, Riverside</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="/series/mapping-companies/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Salesforce</title>
      <link>/companies/mapping-salesforce/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/companies/mapping-salesforce/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/companies/Salesforce_files/figure-html/unnamed-chunk-1-1.png&#34; width=&#34;672&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Salesforce.com dominates the salesforce automation (SFA) and customer relationship management (CRM) space and controls 30% in a highly fragmented market by the end of 2019. The company has added legs to the business clouds, including customer service, marketing automation, e-commerce, analytics, and artificial intelligence. The management has put more emphasis on expanding margins across the clouds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Salesforce.com has assembled a front-office empire that it can build on for years to come. Thanks to the company’s revolution, business software is increasingly accessed through a web browser and delivered over the internet, so inventing the Software-as-a-service (SaaS) software delivery model. Salesforce also offers customers a platform-as-a-service (PaaS) solution, complete with the AppExchange, to rapidly create and distribute apps. This further strengthens the substantial community of Salesforce users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Salesforce is widely considered a leader in its served markets. The tight integration among the solutions and the natural fit they have with one another makes for a powerful value proposition. Indeed, more than half of enterprise customers use multiple clouds. Moreover, customer retention has gradually improved over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Salesforce.com paved the way for the software industry as it exists now by first selling the concept of SaaS to prospective customers and then selling the actual SFA and CRM products. The SaaS model, and SFA and CRM applications, rose in popularity as customers were able to avoid high up-front costs. SaaS vendors benefited from predictable revenue streams, the elimination of piracy, and supporting only one product version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Salesforce.com has gone from no product to 33% market share over the last 20 years. Customers view salesforce as the clear front-runner in a category that increases the productivity of sales representatives. The mission-critical software indeed helps drive revenue for users. Also, customers are reluctant to switch away from the sales cloud because of the time, expense, and lost productivity of retraining the workforce on a new platform. The corporate risk of making a change is high, as executives engage in self- serving behavior. In fact, executives can jeopardize their own careers by pushing to switch from a leading solution that is functioning well and meeting their corporate needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other than the sales cloud, service cloud includes a set of solutions aimed at helping an enterprise deliver customer service and support at scale. Customer service is another mission-critical function that directly helps a company retain customers. Similar to the sales cloud, customers are also reluctant to invest the time and expense of converting a critical revenue-driving function from one application to another. It is often more expensive to find a new customer than it is to retain an existing customer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Salesforce.com has initiated the marketing cloud as one segment under is business clouds umbrella. Marketing automation creates mass-customized cross-platform campaigns to targeted audiences. The company was early to the market with a cloud-based application development platform for customers. Use of the platform provided the low-investment benefits of a SaaS product, allowing for immediate and smooth integration with salesforce.com’s solutions, in which developers can sell or give away the applications they developed on the AppExchange. A variety of publicly traded companies started out as apps developed on the platform and initially distributed on the AppExchange. In fact, AppExchange was a novel idea and predated Apple’s App Store by two years as it was revolutionary and enticing to developers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nvidia</title>
      <link>/companies/mapping-nvidia/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/companies/mapping-nvidia/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/companies/Nvidia_files/figure-html/unnamed-chunk-1-1.png&#34; width=&#34;672&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The increasing complexity of graphics processors provides a barrier to entry for most potential rivals, as it would be challenging to match Nvidia’s large R&amp;amp;D budget. The firm has a first-mover advantage in the autonomous driving market that could lead to widespread adoption of its self-driving platform. The ongoing expansion of artificial intelligence and deep learning that rely on Nvidia ’s graphics chips presented the firm with a potentially massive growth opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PC gaming enthusiasts generally purchase high-end discrete GPUs offered by the likes of Nvidia and AMD. This involves large swaths of data followed by techniques that develop algorithms to produce conclusions in the same way as humans. Today’s basic variants of AI are consumer-based digital assistants, image recognition, and natural language processing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nvidia’s DRIVE PX platform is a deep learning tool for autonomous driving. It is being used in research and development at more than 370 partners. The company views the car as a supercomputer on wheels, although this segment currently contributes relatively little to the top line. Nvidia has patents related to the hardware design of its GPUs in addition to the software and frameworks used to take advantage of GPUs in gaming, design, visualization, and other graphics-intensive applications. The latest pc games typically require system software updates that optimize the performance of GPUs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nvidia has a cost-leadership advantage and intangible assets related to the design of graphics processing units (GPUs). The firm is the originator of and leader in discrete graphics, having captured the lion’s share of the market from longtime rival AMD. The market has significant barriers to entry in the form of advanced intellectual property, as even chip leader intel was unable to develop its own GPUs despite its vast resources and ultimately needed to license IP from Nvidia to integrate GPUs into its PC chipsets. Nvidia has gained share at the expense of AMD as gamers have moved from mainstream graphics cards to performance and enthusiast segments. These GPUs range from $150 at the low-end to over $1,000 for premium cards, with Nvidia’s gaming gross margins in the high 50s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Web behemoths such as Google, Facebook, Amazon, and Microsoft have found GPUs to be adept at accelerating cloud workloads. To train a computer to recognize spoken words or images, it must be exposed to massive amounts of data to educate itself. Conclusions involve taking what the model learned during the training process and putting it into real-world applications to make decisions. The training process is ideal for GPUs that have massively parallel architecture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nvidia has become a key player in the artificial intelligence accelerator market with its GPUs for AI training and possibility workloads. The firm launched its latest A100 data center GPUs. The A100 boasts impressive performance enhancements from its predecessor (V100). Nvidia is the sole beneficiary of the burgeoning ai and self-driving trends. Data center revenue grew considerably, as customers leverage both Nvidia’s training and key AI applications such as natural language processing (NLP).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>