<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Ray K. Yang&#39;s Strategy Thinking</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Ray K. Yang&#39;s Strategy Thinking</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>System Mapping in Business Modeling</title>
      <link>/post/2019/02/28/system-mapping-in-business-modeling/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/02/28/system-mapping-in-business-modeling/</guid>
      <description>In the past several years, I spent quite some time coaching college students in the business major on their individual/team projects. These include business model design (BUS146), strategic audit (BUS109), and marketing plan (BUS103). In each quarter, there are around 100 students enrolled in BUS103/BUS109, and 50 in BUS146. And they typically select different companies and different entrepreneurship ideas to work on.
At some point, I realized it is crucial for them to quickly “model” a business so they can have a very clear picture of how businesses work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Quick Bibliometric Analysis on “Positioning”</title>
      <link>/post/2019/02/26/a-quick-bibliometric-analysis-on-strategic-positioning/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/02/26/a-quick-bibliometric-analysis-on-strategic-positioning/</guid>
      <description>I had a whim and wanted to do some quick bibliometric analysis on the topic of “strategic positioning”.
The raw data is extracted from Web of Science. The search parameters:
TITLE: (&amp;quot;strategic positioning&amp;quot; OR &amp;quot;industry positioning&amp;quot; OR &amp;quot;market positioning&amp;quot;) Refined by: WEB OF SCIENCE CATEGORIES: ( MANAGEMENT OR BUSINESS OR ECONOMICS ) AND WEB OF SCIENCE CATEGORIES: ( MANAGEMENT OR BUSINESS OR INTERNATIONAL RELATIONS OR ECONOMICS ) AND DOCUMENT TYPES: ( ARTICLE ) AND LANGUAGES: ( ENGLISH ) Timespan: All years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimal Positioning for Firms and Individuals</title>
      <link>/post/2019/02/25/optimal-positioning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/02/25/optimal-positioning/</guid>
      <description>Imagine you are invited to a party. Probably you want to get noticed by other partygoers. Or at least you want to be recognized as a cool person by those who you are interested in and care about. The “coolness” will result in some social benefits you desire. This scene is about “social evaluation,” which applies to both individuals and firms. On the social evaluation stage, because there are peer actors (competitors) joining you, you want to stand out of the crowd to impress your audiences (customers and suppliers).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About This Blog</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Hello! I am a Ph.D. candidate in strategic management @ University of California, Riverside.
My research concerns the interplay between business/corporate strategy and the categorical/social structure of the market.
Applying machine learning in strategy is fun. As we envision and observe how things connect, our minds naturally turn to what makes them tick.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>