<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Companies on Rui Yang | Ray Yang, Strategy, U. California, Riverside</title>
    <link>/companies/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Companies on Rui Yang | Ray Yang, Strategy, U. California, Riverside</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="/companies/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Costoco</title>
      <link>/companies/mapping-costoco/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/companies/mapping-costoco/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/companies/Costco_files/figure-html/unnamed-chunk-1-1.png&#34; width=&#34;672&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Costco’s membership renewal rates in the united states and Canada have remained at roughly 90 %. The traffic - driving values that Costco offers in its stores is fueled by cost leverage and procurement strength that, in turn, feeds additional store visits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Costco has achieved a competitive advantage based on its intangible assets and cost leadership. The firm’s membership subscription model has held steady through the financial crisis, the rise of Amazon and its Prime memberships. In addition to cost management and distribution leverage, Costco’s low prices are enabled by its procurement strength.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Costco sells roughly 3,700 different stock - keeping units in its stores, a fraction of the 75,000 to 80,000 at Walmart in the United States. The retailer offers a significantly higher number of items via its marketplace. Costco’s sales per SKU were over 30 million, towering above Walmart’s less than 3 million and target’s $1 million, contributing to its procurement cost advantage.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Costco benefits from a number of traffic drivers, particularly its food offerings ( 53 % of fiscal 2019 sales ) and fuel. Fuel sales serve as a meaningful counterpoint to traffic pressure from digital sellers. With in-store prepared food offerings and a well-developed private - label portfolio, Costco’s store offering is well distinguished. With in-store ready food offerings, the Kirkland signature brand, accounts for around a quarter of Costco’s sales, excluding fuel and is also margin- accretive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Costco has been increasing its e-commerce efforts ( roughly 4 % of sales ), focusing on items not available in stores ( including travel and other services ) and a distinguished product novelty. The digitization of retail has strained all traditional sellers, but we believe it is better placed than most. Costco’s e-commerce efforts are currently focused on items that it doesn’t offer in stores.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An acceleration in the digitization of retail could affect Costco’s results. Pressure should intensify on traditional rivals to deliver omnichannel solutions that incur added payment costs. The pressure should intensify on traditional competitors to provide omnichannel solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The firm has thrived under a variety of conditions, but as competition increases and it expands into new markets, the degree of difficulty also rises. Costco also handles a significant amount of customer data, and a breach could expose it to financial and reputational risk. The firm also faces several costs that are, at least in large part, outside its control, including wages (particularly its gaps against competitors), currency, trade policy, and the broader macroeconomic environment. Costco has worked under a different system, but it faces a number of costs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uber</title>
      <link>/companies/mapping-uber/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/companies/mapping-uber/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/companies/Uber_files/figure-html/unnamed-chunk-1-1.png&#34; width=&#34;672&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Uber ’s position in the autonomous vehicle race could equalize gross and net revenue, after no longer needing to pay drivers. Uber technologies have matched riders with drivers completing trips over billions of miles. At the end of 2019, Uber had 111 million users who used the firm’s ridesharing or food delivery services at least once a month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Uber helps people get from point A to point B by taking ride requests and matching them with drivers available in the area. The firm refers to this as personal mobility, which also shorter - distance transportation via electronic bikes and scooters. Uber faces stiff competition from players such as Lyft (in the U.S.) and didi, a business in which uber has a 20 % holding after the sale of its operations in China to didi in 2016. while uber no longer operates in China, it does compete with didi in other regions around the world. The market remains fragmented, and uber competes with many local ridesharing platforms and taxis. Globally, the market is fragmented. Uber has a 30% global market share and will be the leader in the total addressable ridesharing market ( excluding China ) by 2024.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The firm ’s food delivery service will be one of the main revenue growth drivers for the firm as it will benefit from cross-selling to its large ridesharing user base. Further, utilize of uber ’s overall on-demand platform can also help the firm progress toward profitability. Uber has been in talks to acquire Grubhub in an all-stock deal for each Grubhub share. The addition of GrubHub could strengthen the supply and demand sides of uber ’s network effect moat source. On the supply side, the firm would be better able to attract and retain restaurants. With more food delivery requests, uber is likely to also maintain more of its ride-hailing drivers. Also, this may not only reduce diner acquisition costs for uber but will also allow uber to more effectively cross-sell its two main businesses to a larger user base.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ridesharing platform benefits from network effects and valuable intangible assets in the form of user data. These sustainable competitive advantages will help uber to become profitable and generate excess returns on invested capital. Uber ’s network effects benefit drivers and riders, creating a continuous virtuous cycle. As the number of drivers increased, the timeliness and reliability of the service improved. The riders on the platform benefit as more drivers are added, and existing drivers benefit from more riders, making the driver ’s use even more efficient. The increase in vehicle capacity usage is growing in the average number of rides dispatched per unique uber vehicle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As uber benefits from its network effect, it gains access to valuable intangible assets in the form of user data, which helps the firm improve its services. In turn, Uber ‘s service may become more effective as it further monetizes real-time supply and demand-driven pricing. Uber may also use extensive data and knowledge to tap into other markets. Uber may use this data to tap into other markets. The firm may also increase its vehicles’ capacity usage. The firm compiles data from the rider app about the locations users request rides to and from and at what times of the day. When combined with the user-generated driver ratings, we think such information helps uber improve the timeliness of matching riders with drivers. Such overall enhancement in service could help the firm strengthen its network effect by increasing users and ride requests per user, which helps uber gather additional data.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Salesforce</title>
      <link>/companies/mapping-salesforce/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/companies/mapping-salesforce/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/companies/Salesforce_files/figure-html/unnamed-chunk-1-1.png&#34; width=&#34;672&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Netflix</title>
      <link>/companies/mapping-netflix/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/companies/mapping-netflix/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/companies/Netflix_files/figure-html/unnamed-chunk-1-1.png&#34; width=&#34;672&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft</title>
      <link>/companies/mapping-microsoft/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/companies/mapping-microsoft/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/companies/Microsoft_files/figure-html/unnamed-chunk-1-1.png&#34; width=&#34;672&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Modularization creates servitizatrion.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nvidia</title>
      <link>/companies/mapping-nvidia/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/companies/mapping-nvidia/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/companies/Nvidia_files/figure-html/unnamed-chunk-1-1.png&#34; width=&#34;672&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google</title>
      <link>/companies/mapping-google/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/companies/mapping-google/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/companies/Google_files/figure-html/unnamed-chunk-1-1.png&#34; width=&#34;672&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Facebook</title>
      <link>/companies/mapping-facebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/companies/mapping-facebook/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/companies/Facebook_files/figure-html/unnamed-chunk-1-1.png&#34; width=&#34;672&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebook ’s ad revenue per user has been growing continuously, demonstrating the value that advertisers see in working with the firm. The application of AI technology to Facebook ’s various offerings, along with the launch of VR products, will increase user engagement, driving further growth in advertising revenue. Facebook provides the most massive audience and the most valuable data for social network online advertising.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The firm’s Facebook app, along with Instagram, Messenger, and WhatsApp, is among the world’s most widely used apps on both Android and iPhone smartphones. Facebook is taking steps to further monetize its various Apps, such as providing interactive video ads. The firm is also applying artificial intelligence and virtual and augmented reality technologies to various products, which may increase Facebook user engagement even further, helping to further generate attractive revenue growth from advertisers in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company’s main offerings all have strong network effects. These network effects serve to both create barriers to success for new social - network upstarts as well as barriers to exit for existing users who might leave behind friends, contacts, pictures, memories, and more by departing to alternative platforms. Facebook has emerged and established itself as the clear-cut social media leader.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebook has also slowly become an entertainment hub, which helps increase engagement and user time spent on Facebook. The users are posting more videos and providing a live video feed from where they are at a certain point in time. Additional apps created by developers on the Facebook platform also help maintain users within the Facebook ecosystem. Users are on Facebook and Instagram a combined 65 minutes per day (compared with a daily 64 - minute average during 2016 - 2018 ) posting videos and photos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike any other online platform globally, Facebook has accumulated data about everyone with Facebook and/or an Instagram account. Without the need for cookies enabled on desktop or mobile browsers, the firm knows its users ’ browsing history on many non-Facebook sites or apps. With access to such data and to billions of photos and videos uploaded by its users, Facebook continues to enhance the social network by offering even more relevant content. This positive feedback loop further increases the value of its data asset, which only Facebook and its advertising partners can monetize. Specifically, Facebook monetizes user information only by using it to increase the effectiveness of its advertisers. Advertisers ’ willingness to use Facebook is demonstrated by the 26 % average annual growth of Facebook ’s average ad revenue per user (ARPU), during the past five years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebook ’s large and growing user base and the rich data that it generates help advertisers post more effective target ads, in terms of brand awareness, resulting in a high return on investment (ROI). Most Facebook users are now accessing Facebook and its apps via mobile devices. Thus, the main driver behind the growth of online advertising has been the mobile advertising market and video advertisers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The firm ’s management has demonstrated its focus on long-term returns on investments. With a large amount of cash, along with little debt, Facebook is well-positioned to make additional investments in acquisitions or more research and development. The firm will continue to make decisions regarding capital allocation that are beneficial for its social network users and its shareholders.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple</title>
      <link>/companies/mapping-apple/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/companies/mapping-apple/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/companies/Apple_files/figure-html/unnamed-chunk-1-1.png&#34; width=&#34;672&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apple has plenty of opportunities to reap the rewards of its iPhone business. Apple’s iPhone and IOS operating systems have consistently been rated at the head of the pack in terms of customer loyalty, engagement, and security, which bodes well for long-term customer retention. Apple pay, Apple Watch, Apple TV, and Airpods are also driving incremental revenue and helping to retain iPhone users over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apple’s walled garden approach for its popular iOS allows it to charge a premium for relatively commoditized hardware not too different from that sold by companies like Samsung, and Dell. Customer switching costs are elevated for Apple users as a non-apple IOS experience does not exist. Unlike computing platforms for the windows or android ecosystems that boast PCs and smartphones, Apple enjoys stellar returns on its devices by offering unique user experiences with its iOS ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The robust App store helped foster iPhone adoption and grew Apple’s user base, with applications ranging from productivity, social media, gaming, and so on. Apple has also been focusing on newer software and services to augment the user experience and retain customers. For Apple’s customers, few other technology titans are offering comparable expertise in both hardware and software design, which allows the firm to more seamlessly build integrated products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Competitors such as Samsung and Google specialize in hardware and software, respectively. But neither Samsung nor Google has been able to offer a comprehensive and integrated product like the iPhone. Both have attempted to develop software or operating systems (Samsung’s Tizen OS) and hardware (Google’s Pixel smartphone). Nonetheless, Apple’s expertise in both hardware and software represents an intangible asset that even the strongest of tech firms have struggled to replicate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The active base of apple devices reached 1.5 billion at the end of 2019, up from 1. 4 billion a year prior, showing the strong stickiness Apple has created. These switching costs are not insurmountable, illustrated by the rise and fall of former mobile device titans such as Nokia, Motorola, and Blackberry. Apple may not be immune to pitfalls, as consumer sentiment for technology gadgets can be unforgiving, with one buggy or subpar product potentially driving customers to other companies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apple’s integration of hardware and software also supports its developer networks. Apple iOS will be loaded on to only a handful of screen sizes or iPhone models, versus the hundreds of devices and manufacturers that support android. This leads to a more fragmented Android ecosystem, which is relatively harder for developers to support. Some competitors are willing to sell hardware at essentially cost to drive revenue or stickiness in other business segments. A recent focus on AI assistants such as Google Now and Amazon Alexa has also put pressure on apple’s Siri that has fallen behind its peers in efficacy. Herein lies another area Apple may face headwinds if consumers further prioritize voice-recognition capabilities. Apple’s device may be at risk as it is not likely to supersede their iOS counterparts.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon</title>
      <link>/companies/mapping-amazon/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/companies/mapping-amazon/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/companies/Amazon_files/figure-html/unnamed-chunk-1-1.png&#34; width=&#34;672&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amazon dominates North America ’s online retail category with estimated gross merchandise volume (GMV) of approximately $275 billion in the region during 2019. With more than half of the world ’s internet users coming from developing markets, Amazon has ample international growth opportunities for its marketplaces, cloud services, advertising, and devices. Amazon’s device portfolio - including Kindle, Fire TV, Dash, Echo, and Alexa - enabled products - are intriguing customer acquisition/retention tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The combination of competitive pricing, unparalleled logistics capabilities and speed, and high- level customer service makes Amazon an increasingly vital distribution channel for consumer brands. Amazon maintains a consumer value proposition by expediting the Prime shipping and expanding digital content library, and new member benefits. As the traditional brick-and-mortar retail industry has undergone a period of rapid transformation over the past several years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amazon generates strong cash flow from seller services, which is reinvested in advertising, service, and website enhancements that keep its marketplace strong. Amazon’s brand has come to represent low prices, a wide selection, convenience, and superior customer service — a rare combination among retailers. Amazon ’s operational efficiency of the distribution network, which satisfies consumer demand for free and expedited shipping.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amazon benefits from a network effect, as low prices, an expansive breadth of products, and a user-friendly interface attract millions of customers, which in return, attract merchants of all kinds to amazon.com. Customer reviews, product recommendations, and wish lists increase in relevance as more consumers and products are added to the amazon platform, enhancing its network effect. The customer reviews and product recommendations are growing in presence as more retailers are adding to the site, enhancing the network effect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amazon has continued to develop into a formidable player in digital media, given its vast content offerings, into new verticals, and the ability to sell hardware. Amazon ’s cloud computing offerings possess more than 3 times the computing capacity in use than the next 10 largest providers combined. With investments in additional capacity and other innovations, AWS has become an increasingly positive gross margin contributor.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alibaba</title>
      <link>/companies/mapping-alibaba/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/companies/mapping-alibaba/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/companies/Alibaba_files/figure-html/unnamed-chunk-1-1.png&#34; width=&#34;672&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>