<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>business on Yang&#39;s Strategy Thinking</title>
    <link>/categories/business/</link>
    <description>Recent content in business on Yang&#39;s Strategy Thinking</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/business/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A.I./Blockchain Adoption and Technology Substitution</title>
      <link>/post/2019/04/02/a-i-blockchain-related-m-as-and-technology-substitution/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/04/02/a-i-blockchain-related-m-as-and-technology-substitution/</guid>
      <description>Artificial intelligence (A.I.) and blockchain are the hottest new technologies right now. It would be fun to think about the future of them. Would A.I. and blockchain be the next internet, which has disrupted many traditional business models and creates many new giants across the globe? Or, since businesses have learned a lesson from the internet disruption, A.I. and blockchain will be merely incorporated into the existing technology terrain as an expansion of opportunities by the incumbents?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Summary of Recent &#34;Social Evaluation&#34; Research</title>
      <link>/post/2019/03/25/social-evaluation-and-institutional-complexity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/03/25/social-evaluation-and-institutional-complexity/</guid>
      <description>1 Motivation 2. Biblio-Analysis 2.1 Selection Criteria 2.2 Central Sources and Keywords  3 Classic Papers 3.1 Top Citations 3.2 Summary of Top-cited Papers    1 Motivation The goal of this post is to analyze and review the “social evaluation” research tracing back to Zuckerman (1999)1. The analysis/review is based on hand-collected papers that directly and indirectly cite Zuckerman (1999). The review is not intended to be comprehensive but to understand the central ideas on the topic developed by management/sociology scholars in the past 20 years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interoperability in Tech. Evolution—Thoughts on “Reticulate&#34;</title>
      <link>/post/2019/03/11/interoperability-in-technology-evolution-thoughts-on-reticulate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/03/11/interoperability-in-technology-evolution-thoughts-on-reticulate/</guid>
      <description>On March 6th, the R package “reticulate”(1.11.1) was released on Cran, which allows R users to directly call Python objects or use Python in an R interface.1 Bloggers have been praising this development for the ground-breaking interoperability between R and Python. With “reticulate,” we no longer need to jump between different IDEs to leverage the complementarity between R and Python. This will certainly bring big ease to the programming routine of many “bilingual” data scientist using both R and Python.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>System Mapping in Business Modeling</title>
      <link>/post/2019/02/28/using-system-map-in-business-modeling/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/02/28/using-system-map-in-business-modeling/</guid>
      <description>In the past several years, I spent quite some time coaching college students in the business major on their individual/team projects. These include business model design (BUS146), strategic audit (BUS109), and marketing plan (BUS103). In each quarter, there are around 100 students enrolled in BUS103/BUS109, and 50 in BUS146. And they typically select different companies and different entrepreneurship ideas to work on.
At some point, I realized it is crucial for them to quickly “model” a business so they can have a very clear picture of how businesses work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimal Positioning for Firms and Individuals</title>
      <link>/post/2019/02/25/optimal-positioning-for-firms-individuals/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/02/25/optimal-positioning-for-firms-individuals/</guid>
      <description>Imagine you are invited to a party. Probably you want to get noticed by other partygoers. Or at least you want to be recognized as a cool person by those who you are interested in and care about. The “coolness” will result in some social benefits you desire. This scene is about “social evaluation,” which applies to both individuals and firms. On the social evaluation stage, because there are peer actors (competitors) joining you, you want to stand out of the crowd to impress your audiences (customers and suppliers).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>