<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>market categories on Ray K. Yang&#39;s Strategy Thinking</title>
    <link>/tags/market-categories/</link>
    <description>Recent content in market categories on Ray K. Yang&#39;s Strategy Thinking</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/market-categories/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A (Rough) Bibliometric Analysis on “Strategic Positioning”</title>
      <link>/post/2019/02/26/a-rough-bibliometric-analysis-on-strategic-positioning/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/02/26/a-rough-bibliometric-analysis-on-strategic-positioning/</guid>
      <description>I had a whim and wanted to do some quick bibliometric analysis on the topic of “strategic positioning”.
The raw data is extracted from Web of Science. The search parameters:
TITLE: (&amp;quot;strategic positioning&amp;quot; OR &amp;quot;industry positioning&amp;quot; OR &amp;quot;market positioning&amp;quot;) Refined by: WEB OF SCIENCE CATEGORIES: ( MANAGEMENT OR BUSINESS OR ECONOMICS ) AND WEB OF SCIENCE CATEGORIES: ( MANAGEMENT OR BUSINESS OR INTERNATIONAL RELATIONS OR ECONOMICS ) AND DOCUMENT TYPES: ( ARTICLE ) AND LANGUAGES: ( ENGLISH ) Timespan: All years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimal Positioning for Firms and Individuals</title>
      <link>/post/2019/02/25/optimal-positioning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/02/25/optimal-positioning/</guid>
      <description>Imagine you are invited to a party. Probably you want to get noticed by other partygoers. Or at least you want to be recognized as a cool person by those who you are interested in and care about. The “coolness” will result in some social benefits you desire. This scene is about “social evaluation,” which applies to both individuals and firms. On the social evaluation stage, because there are peer actors (competitors) joining you, you want to stand out of the crowd to impress your audiences (customers and suppliers).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>