<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>strategy on Yang&#39;s Strategy Thinking</title>
    <link>/categories/strategy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in strategy on Yang&#39;s Strategy Thinking</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="/categories/strategy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A.I./Blockchain Adoption and Technology Substitution</title>
      <link>/post/2019/04/02/a-i-blockchain-related-m-as-and-technology-substitution/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/04/02/a-i-blockchain-related-m-as-and-technology-substitution/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;Artificial intelligence (A.I.) and blockchain are the hottest new technologies right now. It would be fun to think about the future of them. Would A.I. and blockchain be the next internet, which has disrupted many traditional business models and creates many new giants across the globe? Or, since businesses have learned a lesson from the internet disruption, A.I. and blockchain will be merely incorporated into the existing technology terrain as an expansion of opportunities by the incumbents? Do A.I. and blockchain have the same fate?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been leaving an eye on the adoption/acquisition of new technology in the banking sector (since one of my dissertation chapters was on banking acquisitions). Here is some latest news.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol style=&#34;list-style-type: decimal&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.slideshare.net/accenture/machine-learning-in-banking&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;According to Accenture, the banking sector has a bright prospect incorporating the A.I. in its six core functions.&lt;a/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cnbc.com/2019/02/13/jp-morgan-is-rolling-out-the-first-us-bank-backed-cryptocurrency-to-transform-payments--.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;JP Morgan has adopted cryptocurrency in the payment businesses.&lt;a/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cnbc.com/2019/03/28/wells-fargo-mastercard-ceos-say-blockchain-has-yet-to-live-up-to-the-hype.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Wells Fargo and Mastercard CEOs express doubt about blockchain.&lt;a/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.coindesk.com/paypal-makes-its-first-ever-investment-in-a-blockchain-startup?hootPostID=71e9a7b4bdfd9e25a696028bb9a83237&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;PayPal made a major investment on the blockchain.&lt;a/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Could there be a unified explanation for what is happening right now? Well, one may associate the topic of technology development with Clayton Christensen’s ‘innovator’s dilemma’ assertion, which predicts emerging new technology will quickly take over declining old ones (often depicted as the double-S curves). It’s the good management–trying best to hear about customer needs, play with competition carefully, and align resource allocation with calculated risk/benefit profiles–who prevent the incumbents from adopting new technologies. Then shouldn’t managers try their best? According to Clayton Christensen, it is difficult for good management not to do good–it is difficult for the incumbents to utilize new technologies even they tend to spot them earlier than startups. At the initiation stage of new technology, incumbents can’t risk their existing market share and customer relationships with unproven models, whereas startups have little to lose. The prediction is: startups disrupt incumbents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, things are different right now. The boundary between new tech. and old tech. are melting down; they are intertwined ecosystems rather than isolated communities. Incumbents right now have taken deliberate effort and allocate resource for emerging technology. They are agiler and more determined to disrupt themselves before being disrupted by others. If important pre-existing conditions are different, it might be necessary to modify the predictions from Clayton Christensen’s double-S curves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, the compatibility between incumbents’ existing technology and emerging technology should lower the likelihood and rate of disruption. Let’s consider two cases here. One is about different incumbent technologies: as compared to traditional banking, the higher level of digitization of PayPal allows a higher compatibility potential with blockchain (consider internet and blockchain don’t rely on a central authority/agency as traditional banking does). The other is about different emerging technologies: as compared to the blockchain, A.I. allows a higher level of compatibility with traditional banking (both banking and A.I. are aimed at decision/prediction accuracy and efficiency.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second, the intensity of the incumbent technology expansion should also lower the likelihood of disruption. This factor is not only related to incumbents’ existing resource base but also has something to do with management. A recent paper in SMJ&lt;a href=&#34;#fn1&#34; class=&#34;footnoteRef&#34; id=&#34;fnref1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; has updated the “double-S” framework by incorporating the “incumbent technology expansion” in predicting the rate of substituion and found empirical support for the model’s prediction efficacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conclusion: since A.I. tends to have a higher level of compatibility with, and also face a stronger expansion threat from, the incumbent technology than blockchain, it’s predicted to have a lower likelihood/rate of disruption. However, contingencies should also exist due to the significant variance in incumbents’ technology, resource, and management conditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn1&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Adner, R., &amp;amp; Kapoor, R. (2016). &lt;a href=&#34;https://scholar.google.com/scholar?hl=en&amp;as_sdt=0%2C6&amp;q=Innovation+ecosystems+and+the+pace+of+substitution%3A+Re-examining+technology+S-curves&amp;btnG=&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Innovation ecosystems and the pace of substitution: Re‐examining technology S‐curves.&lt;a/&gt; Strategic management journal, 37(4), 625-648.&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref1&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Summary of Recent &#34;Social Evaluation&#34; Research</title>
      <link>/post/2019/03/25/social-evaluation-and-institutional-complexity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/03/25/social-evaluation-and-institutional-complexity/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;div id=&#34;TOC&#34;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#motivation&#34;&gt;1 Motivation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#biblio-analysis&#34;&gt;2. Biblio-Analysis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#selection-criteria&#34;&gt;2.1 Selection Criteria&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#central-sources-and-keywords&#34;&gt;2.2 Central Sources and Keywords&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#classic-papers&#34;&gt;3 Classic Papers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#top-citations&#34;&gt;3.1 Top Citations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#summary-of-top-cited-papers&#34;&gt;3.2 Summary of Top-cited Papers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;motivation&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;1 Motivation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of this post is to analyze and review the “social evaluation” research tracing back to Zuckerman (1999)&lt;a href=&#34;#fn1&#34; class=&#34;footnoteRef&#34; id=&#34;fnref1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. The analysis/review is based on hand-collected papers that directly and indirectly cite Zuckerman (1999). The review is not intended to be comprehensive but to understand the central ideas on the topic developed by management/sociology scholars in the past 20 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s continue on the “positioning” topic from &lt;a href=&#34;/post/2019/02/25/optimal-positioning/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;one of my previous posts&lt;/a&gt;(firms are social actors being evaluated by social audiences), but shift our focus of discussion from “what actors do” to “what audience think.” That is, instead of an “actor” standpoint, let’s take an “audience” perspective to consider how firms as market participants are evaluated by market audiences. Reality doesn’t directly translate into human decisions; human beings can only understand reality from their brain, which is subjected to social construction. As a result, the evaluations on market participants do not come from complete rationality in a social vacuum. Rather, audiences’ cognition is shaped by the market’s categorical structure and/or the socially accepted categorical beliefs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;biblio-analysis&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;2. Biblio-Analysis&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;selection-criteria&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;2.1 Selection Criteria&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/post/2019-03-25-social-evaluation-and-institutional-complexity_files/figure-html/unnamed-chunk-2-1.png&#34; width=&#34;672&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/RkzYang/Lit_Review/blob/master/data/savedrecs_cat_eval_032619.txt&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt; raw data&lt;/a&gt; is based on 29 hand-collected papers directed and indirectly citing Zukerman (1999) and extracted from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.webofknowledge.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt; Web of Science&lt;/a&gt;. The papers that not on the topic of “social evaluation” are excluded from the sample, based on the author’s judgment. We can get a general idea of the citation relationship among those papers from the direct citation network graph.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;central-sources-and-keywords&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;2.2 Central Sources and Keywords&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/post/2019-03-25-social-evaluation-and-institutional-complexity_files/figure-html/unnamed-chunk-3-1.png&#34; width=&#34;672&#34; /&gt; By quickly checking the origins (papers being cited) of the sampled papers, we can see that a big portion (the blue-colored cluster) is the classic institution work. It makes sense, as the discussion of the underlying mechanism of social evaluation should be related to how the evaluating standards are formed in the institutionalization processes. The summary in 3.2 will be based on the top-cited “social evaluation” papers in the red-colored cluster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/post/2019-03-25-social-evaluation-and-institutional-complexity_files/figure-html/unnamed-chunk-4-1.png&#34; width=&#34;672&#34; /&gt; The inter-connected keyword clusters present the relationship among the main topics covered by this stream of research. It seems to have a quite strong “strategy” flavor&lt;a href=&#34;#fn2&#34; class=&#34;footnoteRef&#34; id=&#34;fnref2&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. The most frequently used keywords include “industry”, “market”, and “performance.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;classic-papers&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;3 Classic Papers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;top-citations&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;3.1 Top Citations&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;by frequency:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;## [1] &amp;quot;ZUCKERMAN EW, 1999, AM J SOCIOL, V104, P1398, DOI 10.1086/210178&amp;quot;          
## [2] &amp;quot;HSU G, 2006, ADMIN SCI QUART, V51, P420, DOI 10.2189/ASQU.51.3.420&amp;quot;        
## [3] &amp;quot;HSU G, 2009, AM SOCIOL REV, V74, P150, DOI 10.1177/000312240907400108&amp;quot;     
## [4] &amp;quot;PONTIKES EG, 2012, ADMIN SCI QUART, V57, P81, DOI 10.1177/0001839212446689&amp;quot;
## [5] &amp;quot;RAO H, 2005, AM SOCIOL REV, V70, P968, DOI 10.1177/000312240507000605&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;by co-citation centrality:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;## [1] &amp;quot;most central sources (top 5)&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;## ZUCKERMAN EW 1999        HSU G 2009      HSU G 2006-1  PONTIKES EG 2012 
##         1.0000000         0.7142248         0.6970316         0.6754593 
##        RAO H 2005 
##         0.6150981&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most frequent (by frequency count) citations are also the most central (by eigenvector centrality) citations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;summary-of-top-cited-papers&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;3.2 Summary of Top-cited Papers&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hsu et al. (2009) provide an integrative explanation for the multi-category disadvantage. The paper combines the actor- and audience-centered explantions and argues that category spanning is both difficult for the actor to manage and hard for the audience to understand. Hsu (2006) explicitly analyzes the underlying cognition mechanism in which film audiences encounter difficulties in making sense of multi-genre films. Pontikes (2012) analyzes the different segments of market audiences with distinct preferences for ambiguous classification–the difficulty of classifying startups into established categories. According to her, consumers and corporate venture capitalists are more passive market-takers who prefer startups that are easy to classify; in contrast, individual venture capitalists are market-makers who have the power to redefine the market structure and see ambiguous classification as opportunities. Rao et al. (2005) argue that the market boundaries are melting when high-status market participants’ cross the market categories–French chefs with starts in the &lt;i&gt;Guide Michelin&lt;/i&gt; make hybrid cuisines. Typically, there are cost and risk associated with “cross-category borrowings.” But they tend to attenuate when borrowings prevail. Overall, it seems to be risky to cross the categorical boundaries. But contextual contingencies for the benefit/risk profile of category-straddling exists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;References:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zuckerman, E. W. (1999). &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.journals.uchicago.edu/doi/abs/10.1086/210178&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The categorical imperative: Securities analysts and the illegitimacy discount&lt;/a&gt;. American Journal of Sociology, 104(5), 1398-1438.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hsu, G., Hannan, M. T., &amp;amp; Koçak, Ö. (2009). &lt;a href=&#34;https://scholar.google.com/scholar?hl=en&amp;as_sdt=0%2C5&amp;q=Two+sides+of+the+same+coin%3A+How+ambiguous+classification+affects+multiple+audiences%E2%80%99+evaluations&amp;btnG=#d=gs_cit&amp;u=%2Fscholar%3Fq%3Dinfo%3Ah4EhB9sADWIJ%3Ascholar.google.com%2F%26output%3Dcite%26scirp%3D0%26hl%3Den&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Multiple category memberships in markets: An integrative theory and two empirical tests&lt;/a&gt;. American Sociological Review, 74(1), 150-169.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hsu, G. (2006). &lt;a href=&#34;https://scholar.google.com/scholar?hl=en&amp;as_sdt=0%2C5&amp;q=Jacks+of+all+trades+and+masters+of+none%3A+Audiences%27+reactions+to+spanning+genres+in+feature+film+productio&amp;btnG=&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Jacks of all trades and masters of none: Audiences’ reactions to spanning genres in feature film production&lt;/a&gt;. Administrative Science Quarterly, 51(3), 420-450.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pontikes, E. G. (2012). &lt;a href=&#34;https://scholar.google.com/scholar?hl=en&amp;as_sdt=0%2C5&amp;q=Two+sides+of+the+same+coin%3A+How+ambiguous+classification+affects+multiple+audiences%E2%80%99+evaluations&amp;btnG=&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Two sides of the same coin: How ambiguous classification affects multiple audiences’ evaluations&lt;/a&gt;. Administrative Science Quarterly, 57(1), 81-118.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rao, H., Monin, P., &amp;amp; Durand, R. (2005). &lt;a href=&#34;https://scholar.google.com/scholar?hl=en&amp;as_sdt=0%2C5&amp;q=Border+crossing%3A+Bricolage+and+the+erosion+of+categorical+boundaries+in+French+gastronomy&amp;btnG=&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Border crossing: Bricolage and the erosion of categorical boundaries in French gastronomy&lt;/a&gt;. American Sociological Review, 70(6), 968-991.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn1&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The central idea of this paper is that firms’ stock price is affected by the categorical pattern of financial analysts’ industry coverage, which reflects the institionalized expectations for firms’ product mix straddling across various market categories.&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref1&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn2&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;For the central topics in strategy research, refer to “&lt;a href=&#34;https://scholar.google.com/scholar?hl=en&amp;as_sdt=0%2C5&amp;q=The+intellectual+structure+of+the+strategic+management+field%3A+An+author+co-citation+analysis&amp;btnG=&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;the intellectual structure of the strategic management field…&lt;/a&gt;” by Nerur et al. (2008) and “&lt;a href=&#34;https://scholar.google.com/scholar?hl=en&amp;as_sdt=0%2C5&amp;q=What+is+strategic+management%2C+really%3F+Inductive+derivation+of+a+consensus+definition+of+the+field&amp;btnG=&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;what is strategic management…&lt;/a&gt;” by Nag el al. (2007)&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref2&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimal Positioning for Firms and Individuals</title>
      <link>/post/2019/02/25/optimal-positioning-for-firms-individuals/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/02/25/optimal-positioning-for-firms-individuals/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;Imagine you are invited to a party. Probably you want to get noticed by other partygoers. Or at least you want to be recognized as a cool person by those who you are interested in and care about. The “coolness” will result in some social benefits you desire. This scene is about “social evaluation,” which applies to both individuals and firms. On the social evaluation stage, because there are peer actors (competitors) joining you, you want to stand out of the crowd to impress your audiences (customers and suppliers). If you succeed, the peers will admire you, the audiences will adore you, and of course, you can profit from winning the esteems and relationships. The question is, “how to position yourself to be ‘cool’ to win the game?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Practically, the first question coming to your mind might be “to what extent should I be similar to or different from others?” You obviously want to be different so that you can stand out. But you don’t want to be too different as that people think you are wired. Your goal is to “impress” them but not to “surprise” them. The difference between the two is whether you meet their expectations. The audiences have expectations on your appearances and behaviors. It can take the form of a set of commonly accepted attributes and behaviors. Those are “norms.” Importantly, you will be penalized if you fail to meet people’s expectations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being different is risky. Especially when it leads to a failure in meeting audience expectations, you will lose their acceptance, which sociologists call “legitimacy”. Consequently, you lose access to valuable resources and opportunities. Now you get the headache — being similar can’t make you stand out but being different places you into the danger of losing legitimacy. A simple solution, not necessarily simplistic, is to find a middle point between the two extremes — “be as legitimately different as possible.” This is a “holistic” approach, in which you consider all the audiences, attributes, and evaluation processes as a “whole”. And you have a clear goal—maximizing the total audience perceptions. It is also implementable, isn’t it? It reminds me of Confucius’ &amp;amp; Aristotle’s “Golden Mean.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alternatively, we can do some “analysis”.&lt;a href=&#34;#fn1&#34; class=&#34;footnoteRef&#34; id=&#34;fnref1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Then, let’s move away from the “holistic” approach and do some analysis of the positioning problem. Specifically, let’s separate the whole problem in three ways: (1) separating the audiences, (2) separating the actor attributes, and (3) separating the evaluation processes. First, different audience groups (government, customers, investors, etc.) may demand different levels of conformity vs. differentiation, so you may want to deploy a strategy to target specific audiences. Second, as audiences allocate their decision weights among multiple dimensions of difference, you can conform on most of them and only differentiate on a couple of others (we care about the dress code but worry about the outfit clash). Third, as the audiences typically engage in a categorization process before making the final selection, you can strategize for “entering the final game” and “winning the final game” separately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll be glad if the post triggers your interest (I believe it deserves some more thoughts). As audiences evaluate actors’ objective attributes with their subjective minds, there are numerous factors determining how their opinions aggregate over time and emerge as market behavior. There could also be positive and negative feedback loops for the mutual influence between actor behavior and audience perceptions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;References:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://scholar.google.com/scholar?hl=en&amp;as_sdt=0%2C5&amp;q=To+be+different%2C+or+to+be+the+same%3F+It%E2%80%99s+a+question+%28and+theory%29+of+strategic+balance&amp;btnG=&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt; Deephouse, D. L. 1999. To be different, or to be the same? It’s a question (and theory) of strategic balance. Strategic Management Journal, 20(2): 147–166. &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34; https://scholar.google.com/scholar?hl=en&amp;as_sdt=0%2C5&amp;q=Optimal+distinctiveness+revisited%3A+An+integrative+framework+for+understanding+the+balance+between+differentiation+and+conformity+in+individual+and+organizational+identities&amp;btnG=&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt; Zuckerman, E. W. 2016. Optimal distinctiveness revisited: An integrative framework for understanding the balance between differentiation and conformity in individual and organizational identities. Handbook of Organizational Identity. &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34; https://scholar.google.com/scholar?hl=en&amp;as_sdt=0%2C5&amp;q=Optimal+distinctiveness%3A+Broadening+the+interface+between+institutional+theory+and+strategic+management&amp;btnG=&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt; Zhao, E. Y., Fisher, G., Lounsbury, M., &amp;amp; Miller, D. 2017. Optimal distinctiveness: Broadening the interface between institutional theory and strategic management. Strategic Management Journal, 38(1): 93–113. &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn1&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/analysis&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt; Merriam-Webster&lt;/a&gt; has a definition of “analysis” — “separation of a whole into its component parts.”&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref1&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>