<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cryptoes on Ray Yang, Ph.D.</title>
    <link>/crypto/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cryptoes on Ray Yang, Ph.D.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="/crypto/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Bitcoin Value</title>
      <link>/crypto/bitcoin-value/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/crypto/bitcoin-value/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;div id=&#34;TOC&#34;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#upside&#34; id=&#34;toc-upside&#34;&gt;Upside&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#flip-side&#34; id=&#34;toc-flip-side&#34;&gt;Flip-side&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a world where monkeys from the Web2 jungle are perplexed by humans trading tokens for bananas in the Web3 era, the debate around Bitcoin’s value mirrors a similar situation in human history. There exists a gap between the fading world of traditional finance and the pioneering world of digital assets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;upside&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Upside&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bitcoin’s Value as a Decentralized Asset&lt;/strong&gt;: One of the fundamental appeals of Bitcoin is its decentralization. Unlike fiat currencies, which are controlled and issued by central banks, Bitcoin operates on a decentralized network. This decentralization is viewed as a strength by many, as it reduces reliance on central authorities and is resistant to censorship and manipulation. This aspect offers a unique value proposition, especially in countries with unstable economies or where traditional banking systems are not accessible to everyone.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Store of Value as Digital Gold&lt;/strong&gt;: Bitcoin, often compared to gold for its value as a store of wealth and a scarce commodity—there will only ever be 21 million bitcoins. This scarcity helps protect against inflation, similar to gold. However, Bitcoin’s true value lies beyond physical attributes; it transcends borders and barriers, serving as an exchange medium connecting disparate demand and supply. Though lacking traditional intrinsic value, Bitcoin’s ability to operate globally without the constraints of physical borders or disruptions enhances its appeal as “digital gold.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Technological Innovation and Network Effects&lt;/strong&gt;: The technology underlying Bitcoin, blockchain, is a significant innovation. It offers a secure, transparent, and immutable way of recording transactions. This technology has the potential to revolutionize not just currency, but various sectors like supply chain management, voting systems, and digital identities. The value of Bitcoin, therefore, is also tied to the innovative potential of its underlying technology and the possibilities it opens up beyond being just a currency. As long as people find value in its properties and network, its market value persists.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;flip-side&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Flip-side&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lack of Intrinsic Value&lt;/strong&gt;: Unlike tangible assets like food, which can be eaten, or artwork and jewelry, which can be visually appreciated and worn, Bitcoin does not possess such intrinsic physical qualities. It cannot be utilized in a physical sense. For instance, while you can display a piece of artwork in your home or drive a car, Bitcoin does not offer any physical utility or aesthetic pleasure. It exists purely as a digital entity without any physical form or practical use in the everyday world.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Non-Redeemability&lt;/strong&gt;: Traditional financial instruments like fiat currencies, shares, or gift cards have an issuing authority that provides a form of redemption. For example, a casino chip can be exchanged for cash, and fiat currencies are backed by governments that guarantee their value for transactions and debt servicing. In contrast, Bitcoin lacks such an issuing authority willing to redeem it. Satoshi Nakamoto, the creator of Bitcoin, does not offer any form of redemption for Bitcoins, making them fundamentally different from these traditional financial instruments.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Limited Utility&lt;/strong&gt;: Bitcoin’s utility is limited compared to traditional assets or currencies. For example, you can use fiat currency to buy goods and services almost anywhere, and shares in a company can be redeemed for a share of its assets if it liquidates. Bitcoin, however, cannot be used in such a direct way. It’s not universally accepted for transactions, nor does it provide the holder with a claim on physical assets or services. Its role is more akin to a number in an online game, where its value is not tied to a physical commodity or a guaranteed service, but rather to the collective agreement and interest of its users.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>